

# Kuba Kuźma

Senior Ruby, JavaScript Developer

Full stack developer with more than 15+ years of experience in building web applications. Involved in all stages of the software development life cycle. Passionate about learning new technologies and sharing knowledge.

♠ kubakuzma.com kuba@kubakuzma.com github.com/qoobaa in linkedin.com/in/qoobaa

# **SKILLS**



## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Senior Full Stack Developer**

Triage Inc., Ottawa, Canada (remotely)

October 2018 — December 2024

- developed a data exploration and analysis tool to efficiently manage over 2 TB of Al training data
- streamlined storage and processing of 2M images by migrating to ActiveStorage
- redesigned <u>API</u> to align with a wizard-like <u>UI</u> for 200K customers, simplifying the interface and reducing endpoint count
- rapidly built a skin condition classification tool for 20 dermatologists and a team of <u>GPs</u>, leveraging *Metabase* for accelerated delivery
- optimized staging and production environments seamlessly migrating them out of Kubernetes clusters, deployed with Kamal, resulted in threefold cost reduction

#### **Senior Full Stack Developer**

Freeletics GmbH, Munich, Germany (remotely)

*July 2014 — September 2018* 

- migrated legacy *PHP*-based infrastructure to *Ruby on Rails*, streamlining the tech stack and improving maintainability
- optimized the build process for an *Angular* application, reducing build time tenfold and significantly accelerating development
- designed and implemented a token-based authentication mechanism, introducing access tokens that enabled the extraction of the authentication service and modularization of the *Rails* application
- broke down a monolithic *Rails* application into multiple services (<u>APIs</u>), allowing for separate release cycles for distinct applications (Freeletics Fitness, Freeletics Nutrition, etc.)

# Senior Full Stack Developer

Quickjack Solutions Inc., Ottawa, Canada (remotely)

October 2012 — June 2014

- <u>Canadian Health Registry Database</u> developed a *Ruby on Rails* and *Angular*-based platform that processed nearly \$2M in fees for the client since inception.
- bilingual spatial data visualization tool for <u>Search and Rescue Canada</u> built a single-page application using *Ember*, *Leaflet*, *D3*, and *Crossfilter*, designed to launch from *Microsoft SharePoint* on *Internet Explorer*, enabled in-browser visualization and filtering of 100MB+ *ArcGIS* datasets without server-side code

#### Senior Full Stack Developer

Tiramizoo GmbH, Munich, Germany (remotely)

October 2011 — September 2012

- designed and developed a highly modular <u>API</u> using *Node.js*, deploying it into production, later rewritten to *Ruby on Rails*
- implemented an abstraction layer to enable switching from Google Directions <u>API</u> to alternative providers, resulting in substantial cost savings for the company

### **JavaScript Developer**

Strobe Inc., San Francisco, USA (remotely)

*June 2011 — September 2011* 

- collaborated with a remarkable team, including Yehuda Katz, Carl Lerche, José Valim, Peter Wagenet, Piotr Sarnacki, and others
- developed a social add-on for the Strobe platform that simplified integration with Twitter and Facebook <u>APIs</u>, enhancing the platform's functionality and user experience

# **Ruby on Rails Developer**

Object Reload, Gliwice, Poland

*August 2008 — June 2011* 

• various commercial projects using *Ruby on Rails* (details available upon request)

## **EDUCATION**

#### **MSc in Computer Science**

Silesian University of Technology, Gliwice, Poland

2004-2009

# **LANGUAGES**

- Polish (native)
- English (fluent)
- Spanish (basic)
- German (beginner)